A classic of childish heartache, courage, and laughter!
Captain January is a comedy, family film directed by David Butler.
A little girl named Star lives with a lighthouse keeper
who rescued her when her parents drowned.
A truant officer decides she should go to boarding
school but she's rescued by relatives.
Helen 'Star' Mason, played by Shirley Temple.
Captain January, played by Guy Kibbee.
Captain Nazro, played by Slim Summerville.
Paul Roberts, played by Buddy Ebsen.
Agatha Morgan, played by Sara Haden.
Mrs. Eliza Croft, played by Jane Darwell.
Captain January is a 1936 American musical
comedy-drama film directed by David Butler.
The screenplay by Sam Hellman, Gladys Lehman, and Harry Tugend is based
on the 1890 children's book of the same name by Laura E.
The film stars Shirley Temple, Guy Kibbee, and Sara Haden.
There was a tentative attempt at a copyright renewal, but now the
film is in the public domain due to "a legal loophole".
The film explores themes of boarding school, orphanage, lighthouse keeper   .
The tone is lighthearted.